This year's Batten Shoujo-tai flip side and batten is Seta Sakura's graduation special.
This project was to actually do what Seta wanted to do with the members.
The message to Seta brought tears to my eyes.
Finally, there was a kiyamani happening. Watch until the end.
Next time preview
Good morning!
Good morning, good morning.
Good morning.
I'm going to the location for a backstage batten.
Do you remember?
Yes, I remember.
I'm going to do whatever I want to do.
Let's go to a party.
What did you say you wanted to do?
I thought it'd be fun to have a party with the members.
You did have that, didn't you?
Yes, that's right.
And bungee jumping. We talked about our dreams and went bungee jumping.
We talked about how we wanted to roast marshmallows together at a camping trip.
I've called the group ahead of time because I wanted to surprise them.
The members don't know where we're going, so I'll ask Sakira after we go in.
What did she say she wanted to do?
So we'll go bungee jumping, and everyone will wear eye masks and move to the campsite.
Yes, we're all acting, right?
Okay, I'll give them a great performance.
I'll take care of it.
I can't wait to see how Ai reacts to bungee jumping.
So we're going to surprise them with a bungee jump.
I'm going to the machine room with the other members who don't know anything about it.
Good morning!
Thank you for the event.
I'd like to go to the location for the backstage filming.
Did you hear what's on location today?
No, I haven't.
This time it's about Sakura Seta's graduation.
Thank you very much.
It's a graduation project.
A graduation ceremony?
I'm sure there are many things you'd like to do together, but this time, we're going to do on location what Ms. Seta said she wanted to do.
A lot has happened, but...
Ladies and gentlemen...
What is it?
A bungee jam.
A bungee jam?
Cool.
Everybody wants to jump.
I want to jump.
I've always wanted to jump.
Oh, man.
Really, really, really bad.
Thank you so much.
Oh, yeah?
When you say you want to eat...
So this time, I'd like to do a location shoot that Mr. Seta wants to do.
I don't want to.
I don't want to go.
I don't want to go. I'll turn.
What?
This is it.
I knew it.
Does the eye mask make it quieter?
Ew! Ew! Ew!
He's so cute.
How's Ai?
I'm closed right now.
It's pitch black.
Her eyes are really open, though.
Your eyes are open.
They're sparkling.
Nukoso and his friends are busy with concerts and release events every day.
Good night time.
Good night.
Here we are, everyone.
Oh, no!
It's amazing, isn't it?
I got so wet!
Here.
One, two, one, two.
Is he here yet?
Wait, he's gone.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Okay, everybody turn to your left.
Left? Left?
Which hand?
Left.
Okay, then.
One more step forward.
Forward?
Fall.
Falling.
I'm scared.
Are you ready?
I'm ready!
Then take off your eye mask.
Okay.
Yes, sir!
Oh, what?
Where is it?
I'm not a booboo, but I wanted to do what I wanted to do with that group, and that's what I wanted to do.
me
So this time we're going to visit a glamping facility in Oita Prefecture
Glancia Bep Kanna is a glamping facility located in Oita Prefecture.
All rooms are equipped with a hot spring bath.
You can have a barbecue with your family or friends.
And at night, you can enjoy an extraordinary experience around a bonfire.
It is a popular glamping facility.
Let's do something a little like camping in Setagaya!
Let's see what's next!
Open!
Ta-da!
Wow!
It's so big!
Each one of us is eating about one piece.
That's amazing.
I'm going to try one.
Here you go.
There you go!
Wow!
Looks so delicious!
Very delicious!
Ta-da-da-da!
Yay!
Amazing!
The meat is done!
Thank you so much!
Cheer for me.
Cute.
So cute.
Did you do it like this?
He did it!
Yay!
That's great.
Yukimi.
I just brought it with me.
Thank you.
Oh, there it is!
Bon appétit!
Looks delicious
So soft.
Mmmm
Delicious
Mmmm...
Delicious.
Wow, what, what is this place?
What?
Oh, wow.
Wow, this place looks like it's gonna be fun.
Oh, my God.
Catch day?
The catch.
It's warm. The catch.
Today is the day of the catch.
There's something I want to do over a stampfire.
What?
I had a dream about eating meat earlier, but...
I wanted to do the most.
I'm going to go take some pictures.
What?
It's so cute.
Roasted marshmallows.
That's cute.
I want to do it.
It's a big marshmallow.
They prepared these for us.
Oh, my gosh!
Oh, my God! One?
You mean one marshmallow?
You mean one, right?
Then he'll pass them out.
Stretch this out.
There it is.
This is stretching the suspension pretty hard.
Maybe. Stick it in first, then stretch it.
There's only one, but if you think it's real close, it'll turn black all at once.
Let's, uh, let's all take a look at how it's doing.
Wow!
If it's directly in the fire, it'll be backed up in an instant.
Black on the back.
Black?
If you just look at this main camera, it's like we're fishing.
Let's see what we can catch.
I wonder what we'll catch.
I'd love to catch a big one.
Sakura's looking really good though.
Maybe it's getting better.
Oh, my God!
Mayu this, me too
Mayu now
Mayu work Mother
Oh, no!
Whew!
Looks like it's your birthday!
Happy birthday!
Thank you!
Oh, my God, that's great!
It's like cream puff batter!
Awww!
I had it in the smear in a second.
Riko-chan's Bember.
I'll do my best!
Well then, everyone.
Cheers!
Come on!
Bon appétit!
Oh, and Hiroppi's autograph, too!
Awww!
Bon appétit!
Thank you!
Mmm!
Delicious!
Yum! Yum!
It's amazing!
If only one person came to ripen...
Oh, my God!
Advanced.
Skelly!
This is Sakura Seta's graduation project.
I didn't tell you all from here.
I didn't tell you this, but I'd like to give a message to Sakura one by one.
Ehhhh...
Impossible!
It's definitely Rira-chan!
Let's start with the younger ones.
Let's start with Mie-chan.
I'm about to cry.
Everyone!
I'm going to cry
I joined Batten Shoujo-tai from the middle of the group.
I joined Batten Shoujo-tai in the middle of the group, and we've been working together as six since then.
It's been 3 years and 4 years now, and I have so many memories with Sakura-chan.
And today, we were able to make memories like this at the end...
Congratulations!
I felt so happy.
I ate oshiboro.
I'm really full of it.
Sakura-chan's kindness saved my life.
I really loved, admired and respected you.
I'm sad that I won't be able to work with you anymore.
But I will always love you.
I will always support you.
Good night.
The live in Fukuoka will be our last one.
But I'll be able to say goodbye to Natsukura-chan with lots of love.
I hope I can say goodbye to Natsukura-chan.
I love you so much!
You're a really good singer, Miyu.
She sang so well from the first time she came in.
From now on, she's going to be a member of the excerpts.
I knew that she would be the one to support our future singers.
I was really looking forward to seeing her.
Lately, I've been listening to her so much at her live performances.
I'm really looking forward to seeing you grow even more in the future.
I wish you all the best.
I'll do my best.
Thank you so much, I love you so much.
I love you so much.
I've been in trouble since I came here.
I don't know.
But then I was like...
I felt like a marshmallow.
When Riko...
When she got burned...
I felt sorry for her.
But then...
Inside Rira...
I felt like I'd lost my temper.
Heh heh heh.
After you quit...
Hmm.
I don't know, at first...
I really...
I don't know...
I couldn't sing.
But then...
I don't know.
Singing...
I don't know...
And...
I don't know... I can't... I can't do it.
I practice before a show, when I'm singing, but...
I can't do that either. I can't... I can't...
I'm so sorry, I just can't help it.
But I don't know... maybe at the live concert at the love concert... when I said to the author... something about bye-bye... before...
I was so happy when the author said, "I got it!" It makes me feel like I'm doing my best.
But I still have a lot of things I need to work on.
I still have a lot of things to do, but you said something like that to me little by little.
I feel relieved when they tell me that or when they tell me before a live performance.
I felt relieved.
Thank you very much.
It's me! I love you so much!
I'm sorry I cried a lot.
I'm so happy.
Rirarachan is super fresh.
You're like a pre-cure, you're so energetic.
You are so close to the kind of idol I want to be.
Everyone has their own way of singing.
Rirar-chan gives me courage.
Rirar-chan sings so well.
Because you sing so prettily.
I think it's the kind of song that makes you want to work harder, too.
And her lines are the cutest.
I hope you'll do your best for Oshui's "Awari".
I'll do my best.
I'm a pink Lilah who has so many wonderful things about her.
I hope she will continue to bring her beautiful smile to everyone.
Ai-chan is also on the left, so MC
Ai-chan
I wish you all the best.
I love you so much!
Thank you very much.
You're right.
When I look at you, I see you.
I almost cry when I see your eyes.
I've been with Sakura since before the place was over 10 years old.
I've bumped into Hamo on occasion.
Normal.
I've bumped into Hamo at times.
Sometimes we're like classmates, sometimes we're like business partners, sometimes we're just friends, sometimes we're just friends, sometimes we're just friends.
Our relationship has changed in many ways.
If you look at other places, it's pretty much the opposite of cherry blossoms.
But we haven't crossed paths in other places, and that's why we've been able to be together with Sakura.
That's why I'm so happy to be here with Sakura.
I want to support Sakura as she finds her new dream.
Sakura told me that she's watching me continue to be an idol, so I want to support her in finding her new dream, and I also want her to smile when she sees that.
I hope Sakura will smile when she sees that.
I hope Sakura can see that and smile too.
In this group, we seem to be the closest, but we're really far away.
We seem to be the closest, but we're really far away from each other.
But we're so close.
It's so difficult.
It's because we're really classmates.
I think we have the same feelings.
But we've been working together since we were students.
I've always thought that this idol was the only way for me.
I've been doing this for a long time.
Keena is also working really hard in her studies, and she usually says to me, "I've decided not to go to that university, and I want to continue to be an idol, but I don't know where I want to go.
I was thinking that I wanted to do my best where I wanted to do my best, when I heard that Keena was going to college.
At the time, I didn't know a lot about myself.
I didn't know much about the world around me or anything.
I only understood my own way of thinking, and I was saying things like, "I really want to work hard at this place, but I don't know if I can do it.
And when Keena was trying her best, I let the atmosphere get to her.
It was a little bit too much for me.
Kina is working really hard in her studies and also in her idol career, and it's really difficult for me to balance both of them.
I thought it was really difficult for her to balance both of them.
I thought it was really cool that you were enjoying it so much.
And I'm really happy that we've been able to work together as a group for so long now.
I'm glad we're classmates.
Yes, I am.
I wish we could have been idols together more often.
But you're right.
Kiina, you've been studying and working hard.
Just like Kiina worked so hard on her studies and idols.
I want to like all kinds of things like that.
I've only known idols so far.
I've only known idols until now, so seeing Kiina made me want to work harder.
I know I won't be able to see you as often as I'd like.
I definitely want to go out to dinner with you.
Please let me invite you.
Thank you.
I'm definitely nervous when it's my turn.
But really, you know...
Sakura, as I've said so many times in interviews and stuff, there are so many things that are the exact opposite of what I'm talking about, and I've been wondering...
It's so strange to us that the only difference between MBTI and love.
But when I look back on it like this...
I think that there are so many things that we want to do.
I think there were a lot of things that were the same.
Sakura said earlier that she didn't know much about the people around her.
I was helped and spoiled by Sakura's strength to tell me what to do in those situations.
I was helped by Sakura's strength to speak up in those situations, and I was spoiled.
I felt like she was always one step ahead of me even though I was younger than her.
I felt like she was always one step ahead of me.
So when I heard from Sakura that she was graduating
I wasn't really surprised.
I thought it was really cool that you were going one step ahead of me again.
Of course I feel sad now, but
But even so, this cool Sakura has saved us so much.
And until now...
I think Sakura has given us and Taen-san a lot of things.
Also, we still have the Fukuoka concert, but Sakura got a lot from that too.
I hope the members and Taen-san and I can deliver our love to Sakura so that she will feel like she got a lot of this from us too.
I hope we can continue to grow together with each other and I hope Sakura will be able to be a part of our future.
I hope Sakura will think that the 10 years and 9 years of her time in Arbation was not a waste.
We will do our best from now on.
I hope that Sakura will also feel that her life has not been a mistake.
I hope that Sakura will spend her life in such a way that she can feel that she made the right decision in her life.
Thank you.
Yes, really, I wonder why.
Love and good are the only things that change.
I wonder why it's so different.
I mean, not hitting the ball...
But Rico and I have some kind of goal.
And when I think about what I should do to get there...
We have different ways of doing things, but in the sense of keeping our eyes on the future.
Rico is amazing in the sense that he keeps looking ahead, even though I sometimes think ahead too.
I've always thought that Rico is looking beyond that.
I thought she was the type of girl who could do it easily at first.
I thought she was the type of girl who could comment very well.
Or he knows what he needs to do now.
I always wondered why.
That's why it's red, I think.
Especially recently, she's become a really good MC.
He even reads the news.
It's really great.
She's really great. She said she wanted to be an announcer, too, but...
But after seeing Rico, I realized I'm no good at all.
I can do Rubik's Cube, and I can put my ring finger and cat finger on it.
We should do it together sometime.
You make everyone smile, and I think you're so sparkly and wonderful.
And I'm sure you'll join us as a new member of the group.
I'm sure you'll be a great leader for us.
I'm sure she's going to be a great leader for us.
I think Riko is the reason I'm able to look for my dreams and think about the future.
I think that's why I've been able to look for my dreams and think ahead.
When I'm having a hard time, I want people around me to talk to me about it.
I think there are a lot of things that you work really hard for.
I think there are a lot of things I want you to do.
You always tell me what you want me to do or what I can do to make it better.
I hope you will continue to tell me about your meetings with the members.
I hope you will continue to do so.
I really appreciate you guys.
Thank you for working with us.
Thank you very much.
I'm not used to this.
I'll never get used to it.
This is bad.
I'm a little...
I'm so nervous.
I'm actually...
But actually, bonfire time is almost over.
I have one last thing to say to Ai-chan.
What?
I'm going to make a reservation.
What? Why?
Oh, shit.
What is it? What's this?
Reservation work.
It's nothing.
The members are crying a lot!
And finally, Kiyama's message!
But here's what happened.
The reservation time for the bonfire has already ended.
The next guests are waiting for us.
We'll ask them to send us a message in Aieo-sakusen (Japanese syllabary) at the end.
Okay, bye.
Suddenly I feel like a flip-flopper.
Seto sakura no se
I'll do my best.
Seto-zakura-no-uta.
Lots and lots of love.
Sa...
I get it from Sakura.
Sakura's mouth
Ku!
Coo-coo!
Sakura, you're lucky!
Thank you so much!
I love you so much!
Thank you so much.
I'm just, like, super smitten so far.
Coo.
Coo...
I can really understand why Ai-chan was given the name "Ai" from various points of view.
Ai-chan is the member who has the most fun, and when we talked about what we wanted to do in the future, she said she wanted to do live shows with everyone.
When we talked about what we wanted to do in the future, Ai-chan said that she wanted to perform with everyone and that she enjoys performing live, which made me want to work hard at performing live as well.
There were times when I felt it was a little bit difficult, but even in those times, I got a lot of energy and wanted to stand up on stage with her.
I felt like I wanted to stand on stage with you.
Thank you so much!
Anyway, I'm getting a lot of love from you.
Thank you very much.
Yes, I'll be right back.
Thank you.
Dear Sakura
Thank you for working with me for almost 10 years now.
I really feel like it's still time
I'm excited.
but I don't want to.
I'm trying not to think about it.
I try not to think about it.
But Sakura really helped me a lot
You helped me a lot.
I think
When we all
When we expressed our opinions
or when we were trying to decide what to do...
Sakura would say something to me...
A word or something...
It makes me feel at ease.
I'm sorry.
I often felt "ahaha" and "thank you".
I really felt Sakura's presence in so many situations.
I felt Sakura's presence in so many different situations, and when I think that she will be gone from now on
I'm so anxious about what I'm going to do now that I don't have Sakura anymore.
Sakura left a lot of things to us here at Pattin Shoujo-tai.
She left a lot of things to us here at Pattin Shoujo-tai.
I've felt so many feelings and thoughts from Sakura
I can feel her feelings and thoughts close to me.
I have to do my best more and more.
I have to make it better.
It makes you nervous, doesn't it?
Yes, you're right.
It's so difficult.
Do you remember when I called you a really long time ago, Sakura?
We talked about the future.
It was a long time ago.
I know it's been years, but...
It seems like only yesterday.
From now on...
I'm going to take a different path from now on.
I'll always love you and I'll always support you
And I'll support you the most.
Let's have dinner together again
Let's go out to dinner together again, eat meat and have a lot of fun!
I really, really love you!
Thank you Sakura!
See you soon!